## ANDRE **PEIXOTO**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Phone: +55 18 99790-9068

Email: hi@andrepeixoto.dev

Website: andrepeixoto.dev

LinkedIn: andrempeixoto

Github: andrempeixoto

### **PROFILE**

From the moment I first created a personalized version of an IRC messenger (year 1.999) to writing modern JavaScript code in 2022, I have to say programming has been a lifelong passion. Currently developing modern and performatic PWA apps, I'm excited to use my skills for creating meaningful apps that generate value and revenue.

Below you'll find some projects I've completed that showcase my skills and general background in software development.

### **SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Vue.js
- React.js
- Node.js
- Jest/TDD
- Electron
- Flutter/Dart
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Agile/Scrum
- Jira

- Linux
- Windows
- Portuguese
- English

### **PROJECTS**

#### AMAZON.COM WEBSITE CLONE

- Amazon.com website clone created with ReactJS on the front-end, Stripe for handling payment authentication and Firebase for storing order's history.
- Available here.

#### **VETERINARY CLINIC WEBSITE**

- An institutional website made for Pequenos Animais veterinary clinic.
- Built with React.JS
- The website is currently under development.
- Preview version deployed here.

#### TO-DO APP

- A to-do list app for listing daily activities to get completed.
- Built with React.JS
- · Available here.

#### E-LEARNING PLATFORM

- An e-learning platform build with ReactJS (front-end), Node.js (backend), and sqlite3 for its database;
- Available here.

## **EDUCATION**

GOSTACK BOOTCAMP (MERN) FullStack Web/Mobile, Rocketseat Education, 2021

COMPUTER SCIENCE (CS50X) Software Development, HarvardX, 2021

**BUSINESS MANAGEMENT** 

MBA, Toledo University Center, 2013

**BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES** 

Bachelor's, Northern Parana State University, 2010

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 2021 - PRESENT

#### **FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

## **Twiage**Full-time

 Develop web applications with Vue.js and Node.js, primarily, and also cross-platform applications with Electron and Flutter, collaborating with a team of remote developers.

#### 2021 - 2021

#### FLUTTER DEVELOPER

## **NuoMed**Full-time

 Participated in the early stages of a telemedicine start-up's project building an cross-platform app with Flutter and Dart lang, performing front and back-end programming, and collaborating in the UX design development.

#### 2019 - 2021

#### **ESL TEACHER**

## **CalEnglish**Part-time

 Taught English as a Second Language to beginner, intermediate and advanced levels to Brazilian students in VIP and group classes.

#### 2017 - 2019

#### IT COORDINATOR

## Igreja Prudentina Part-time

 Coordinated media and communication department (sound operation, video streaming of services and courses, monthly newsletters editing, website's development and maintenance).

#### 2015 - 2021

#### IT COORDINATOR & BUSINESS ADVISOR

#### Pequenos Animais Part-time

 Conducted IT management, such as network and applications support, in person and remotely, as well as business consulting services, aiming greater ROI & customer satisfaction.

#### 2014 - 2015

#### CUSTOMER SUPPORT SPECIALIST

#### IBM

Full-time

 Provided remote support for Hardware and Services divisions located in the United States, from Brazil's IBM plant through email, chat and phone.

#### 2011 - 2014

#### **ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER**

## **Pequenos Animais**Full-time

- Developed many initiatives in the IT field for the company regarding its internal communication and scheduling systems (GSuite, web apps, and local network);
- Lead processes' and departments' reorganization and improvement;
- Engaged on the company's brand strengthening, improving and modernizing its marketing initiatives and digital presence;